http://www.echonet.org/privacy-policy

What we do
We don’t just teach farmers, we equip families to change their lives.
Partner With Us
Join the THRIVE Team!
Help families move from barely surviving to thriving when you join the special ECHO Thrive Team. Your monthly gift ensures life-changing trainings and resources are available. For as little as $10 a month, you can make a lasting difference. Monthly giving is a convenient way to give and show you care – with powerful results.
Learn More
Give
Giving Options
Give One Time
Give Monthly
Gift Catalog
Planned Giving
Matching Gifts
IRA Rollovers
Gifts of Stock
Gift Catalog
ECHO’s Online Gift Catalog gives you the opportunity to donate in honor of a loved one. Your hard-earned money will reduce hunger and improve lives worldwide and your recipient will have the heartwarming feeling of knowing that a gift was made in their name!
Learn More
Visit ECHO
Visit ECHO
ECHO Global Farm Tour
Appropriate Technology Tour
Tour Admission
Directions
FAQs
Introducing the ECHOcommunity Mobile App
The ECHOcommunity mobile app was launched on November 19th at
Read More
Latest Stories
Behind the Scenes at an East Africa Workshop
When agricultural lands are depleted or overgrazed, incomes dwindle and
Read More
ECHO Videos
ECHO featured as ‘Inspiring Nonprofit’
ECHO was featured as an inspiring nonprofit on Peacevision.com. Reporting
Read More
About Us
Visit ECHO
Contact
Give
Gift Catalog
Give
Give One Time
Donor Privacy
ECHO Inc. is committed to respecting the privacy of both our online and offline donors. This privacy policy has been developed to ensure our donors that no donor information will be shared with any third party.This Donor Privacy Policy is written to inform our donors and guide our staff on how personal information will be used. We also provide every donor with the opportunity to remove their name(s) (or opt out of) our email or mailing list, when requested to do so.ECHO, Inc. collects and uses information from donors that includes: amount donated, address, telephone number, donor comments and email address. Tax laws in the United States require ECHO, Inc. to keep contact information and contribution level of donors on file.ECHO, Inc. uses donor information to understand donors’ needs and provide excellent service. ECHO, Inc. will never sell, trade, rent or share names, email or mail addresses, or telephone numbers of our donors, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations. All donor transactions such as those indicated below are processed internally by our professional staff:Distribute receipts for donations,Thank donors for their donations,Inform donors about upcoming events and other activities of ECHO, Inc.,Internal analysis and record keeping,Report to relevant U.S. and State agencies,(these reports are not available for public inspection except as required by law)Contact donors about changes to this policy. However, we allow donors the option to be recognized when permission is granted, and, properly anonymized donor information may be used for promotional and fundraising activities.  All access to donor financial information is strictly limited to professional staff of ECHO, Inc. whose job requires them to process this data. No such data is given to any person, organization or group who does not need to access donor data. Donor records are kept in a secure file cabinet.To accept contributions via credit card, ECHO, Inc. uses accredited online payment processing services with world-class security and data privacy policies. Unless requested by the donor for the purpose of processing recurring donations, ECHO Inc. does not store, nor does it have access to, your credit card information, bank account numbers, or other account data sent to those processing services.
Privacy Policy
This Website collects some Personal Data from its Users.
ECHO Inc. will not sell Personal Data to any third party for any purpose.
This document last updated on May 20, 2020.
Some data collected in the act of tracking website use is transferred to third parties. No Personal Data is transferred for this purpose. This, however, is considered to be the sale of data in some legal jurisdictions.
Data provided to ECHO Inc. will be used solely in accordance with the stated purpose.
This document is related to, and when in conflict is superseded by, our Donor Privacy Policy.
Owner and Data Controller
ECHO Inc. – 17391 Durrance Rd. N. Fort Myers, FL 33917
Owner contact email: echo@echonet.org
Owner contact phone number: +1.239.543.3246
Definitions of terms used in this document:
Personal Data (or Data)
Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.
Usage Data
Information collected automatically through this Website (or third-party services employed in this Website), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Website, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.
User
The individual using this Website who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.
Data Subject
The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.
Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)
The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.
Data Controller (or Owner)
The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is ECHO Inc.
This Website
The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.
Service
The service provided by this Website as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.
European Union (or EU)
Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.
Cookies
Small sets of data stored in the User’s device.
Types of Data collected
Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies; Usage Data; first name; last name; phone number; address; country; email address; ZIP/Postal code; city. In addition, bank transfer and credit card data as required by a third-party processor and necessary to complete a transaction may be collected.
Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact ECHO Inc.
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document.
Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to ECHO Inc.
Mode and place of processing the Data
Methods of processing
ECHO Inc. takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to ECHO Inc, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Website (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by ECHO Inc. The updated list of these parties may be requested from ECHO Inc at any time.
Legal basis of processing
The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:
Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations ECHO Inc may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which ECHO Inc is subject;
processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in ECHO Inc;
processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by ECHO Inc or by a third party.
In any case, ECHO Inc will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.
Place
The Data is processed at ECHO Inc’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.
Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.
Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by ECHO Inc to safeguard their Data.
If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with ECHO Inc using the information provided in the contact section.
Retention time
Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose for which they have been collected.
Therefore:
Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between ECHO Inc and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
Personal Data collected for the purposes of ECHO Inc’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by ECHO Inc within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting ECHO Inc.
The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, ECHO Inc may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.
The purposes of processing
The Data concerning the User is collected to allow ECHO Inc to provide its Service, comply with its legal obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Analytics, Contacting the User, processing donations, and Interaction with external social networks and platforms.
For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.
Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data
Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:
Analytics
Contacting the User
Interaction with external social networks and platforms
Processing donations
The rights of Users
Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by ECHO Inc. In particular, Users have the right to do the following:
Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by ECHO Inc, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing, and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, ECHO Inc will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from ECHO Inc.
Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller. Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.
Details about the right to object to processing
Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in ECHO Inc. or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by ECHO Inc, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.
Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether ECHO Inc is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.
How to exercise these rights
Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to ECHO Inc through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by ECHO Inc as early as possible and always within one month.
Additional information about Data collection and processing
Legal action
The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by ECHO Inc. in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related Services.
The User declares to be aware that ECHO Inc may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.
Additional information about User’s Personal Data
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.
System logs and maintenance
For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.
Information not contained in this policy
More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from ECHO Inc at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.
How “Do Not Track” requests are handled
This Website does not support “Do Not Track” requests.
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.
Changes to this privacy policy
The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this page and possibly within this Website and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to ECHO Inc. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, ECHO Inc shall collect new consent from the User, where required.
Information for Californian consumers
This part of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the business running this Website and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries, and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).
The provisions contained in this section apply to all Users who are consumers residing in the state of
California, United States of America, according to “The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018” (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), and, for such consumers, these provisions supersede any other possibly divergent or conflicting provisions contained in the privacy policy.
This part of the document uses the term “personal information“ as it is defined in The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA).
Categories of personal information collected, disclosed or sold
In this section, we summarize the categories of personal information that we’ve collected, disclosed or sold and the purposes thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.
Information we collect: the categories of personal information we collect
We have collected the following categories of personal information about you: identifiers and internet information.
We will not collect additional categories of personal information without notifying you.
How we collect information: what are the sources of the personal information we collect?
We collect the above-mentioned categories of personal information, either directly or indirectly, from you when you use this Website.
For example, you directly provide your personal information when you submit requests via any forms on this Website. You also provide personal information indirectly when you navigate this Website, as personal information about you is automatically observed and collected. Finally, we may collect your personal information from third parties that work with us in connection with the Service or with the functioning of this Website and features thereof.
How we use the information we collect: sharing and disclosing of your personal information with third parties for a business purpose
We may disclose the personal information we collect about you to a third party for business purposes. In this case, we enter a written agreement with such third party that requires the recipient to both keep the personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose(s) other than those necessary for the performance of the agreement.
We may also disclose your personal information to third parties when you explicitly ask or authorize us to do so, in order to provide you with our Service.
To find out more about the purposes of processing, please refer to the relevant section of this document.
Sale of your personal information
For our purposes, the word “sale” means any “selling, renting, releasing, disclosing, disseminating, making available, transferring or otherwise communicating orally, in writing, or by electronic means, a consumer’s personal information by the business to another business or a third party, for monetary or other valuable consideration”.
This means that, for example, a sale can happen whenever an application runs ads, or makes statistical analyses on the traffic or views, or simply because it uses tools such as social network plugins and the like.
Your right to opt-out of the sale of personal information
You have the right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling your data, we will abide by your request.
Such requests can be made freely, at any time, without submitting any verifiable request, simply by following the instructions below.
Instructions to opt-out of the sale of personal information
If you’d like to know more, or exercise your right to opt-out in regard to all the sales carried out by this Website, both online and offline, you can contact us for further information using the contact details provided in this document.
What are the purposes for which we use your personal information?
We may use your personal information to allow the operational functioning of this Website and features thereof (“business purposes”). In such cases, your personal information will be processed in a fashion necessary and proportionate to the business purpose for which it was collected, and strictly within the limits of compatible operational purposes.
We may also use your personal information for other reasons such as for commercial purposes (as indicated within the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document), as well as for complying with the law and defending our rights before the competent authorities where our rights and interests are threatened or we suffer actual damage.
We will not use your personal information for different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without notifying you.
Your California privacy rights and how to exercise them
The right to know and to portability
You have the right to request that we disclose to you:
the categories and sources of the personal information that we collect about you, the purposes for which we use your information and with whom such information is shared;
in case of sale of personal information or disclosure for a business purpose, the personal information categories obtained by each category of the recipient.
The disclosure described above will be limited to the personal information collected or used over the past 12 months.
If we deliver our response electronically, the information enclosed will be “portable”, i.e. delivered in an easily usable format to enable you to transmit the information to another entity without hindrance – provided that this is technically feasible.
The right to request the deletion of your personal information
You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information, subject to exceptions set forth by the law (such as, including but not limited to, where the information is used to identify and repair errors on this Website, to detect security incidents and protect against fraudulent or illegal activities, to exercise certain rights etc.).
If no legal exception applies, as a result of exercising your right, we will delete your personal information and direct any of our service providers to do so.
How to exercise your rights
To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your verifiable request to us by contacting us via the details provided in this document.
For us to respond to your request, it’s necessary that we know who you are. Therefore, you can only exercise the above rights by making a verifiable request which must:
provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collect personal information or an authorized representative;
describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.
We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity and therefore confirm the personal information in our possession actually relates to you.
If you cannot personally submit a verifiable request, you can authorize a person registered with the California Secretary of State to act on your behalf.
If you are an adult, you can make a verifiable request on behalf of a minor under your parental authority.
You can submit a maximum number of 2 requests over a period of 12 months.
How and when we are expected to handle your request
We will confirm receipt of your verifiable request within 10 days and provide information about how we will process your request.
We will respond to your request within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.
Our disclosure(s) will cover the preceding 12 month period.
Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial.
We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable request unless such a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. In such cases, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to act on the request. In either case, we will communicate our choices and explain the reasons behind it.
Legal information
This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).
This privacy policy relates solely to this Website, if not stated otherwise within this document.
Special thanks to iUbenda.com which provides compliance documents and services.
We are voluntarily evaluated for financial transparency and accountability by these independent third-party organizations.
ECHO, Inc. is a 501(c)3 nonprofit organization registered under EIN: 23-7275283.
© Copyright ECHO 2020.
All Rights Reserved.
Privacy Policy | Terms of Service
